<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aaron Berk</title>
    <link>https://aaronberk.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aaron Berk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Aaron Berk</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aaronberk.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Future [Mathematics] Leaders</title>
      <link>https://aaronberk.ca/post/fsld3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaronberk.ca/post/fsld3/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 &amp;mdash; Coding in Python Welcome to Day 3 of the Math section of Future Science Leaders! Today, you will get to explore a series of activities that will have you coding and problem solving in Python. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Python already installed your laptop, no worries! Simply go to repl.it. There should be no need to make an account. We&amp;rsquo;ll be walking around to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re able to get up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection: 2018 BC Data Science Workshop</title>
      <link>https://aaronberk.ca/post/bcdata-workshop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 10:22:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaronberk.ca/post/bcdata-workshop-2018/</guid>
      <description>Summary This is a summary and reflection from co-organizing the second iteration of the BC Data Workshop.
About The BC Data Workshop was hosted June 4 &amp;ndash; 8 on the UBC campus, co-organized with the IAM Director Brian Wetton, supported by PIMS.
The workshop featured a wide array of problem material from industry in the lower mainland, channeled as week-long data science projects led by industry mentors.
Projects Project 1: SSR Mining Participants analyzed over 50 GB of data for particular heavy equipment used in an ongoing mining operation to discover patterns in equipment failure for predictive maintenance strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Links</title>
      <link>https://aaronberk.ca/post/resource-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 14:35:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaronberk.ca/post/resource-links/</guid>
      <description>Links to helpful resources  A 42 video YouTube series by &amp;ldquo;the guy who wrote the Matlab function \&amp;ldquo;. A YouTube series on Conditional Random Fields by Hugo Larochelle. One of myriad Medium lists of ML resources. One more with a link to ≥ 150 tutorials DL book DL.net reading list  Blog-likes that I think are good  Terry Tao&amp;rsquo;s blog Shtetl-Optimized Timothy Gowers&amp;rsquo;s Weblog Variance Explained Steven Strogatz in the New York Times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Completion Whirlwind</title>
      <link>https://aaronberk.ca/post/matrix-completion-whirlwind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 11:47:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaronberk.ca/post/matrix-completion-whirlwind/</guid>
      <description> Summary I recently wrote some basic Python functions for a matrix completion tutorial, covering elementary theory and a couple popular convex optimization methods for matrix completion.
The repository is available on GitHub, including the Jupyter notebook, which can be viewed on GitHub, as a gist, or below.
Matrix completion whirlwind gist  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection: 2017 BC Data Science Workshop</title>
      <link>https://aaronberk.ca/post/bcdata-workshop-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 19:47:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaronberk.ca/post/bcdata-workshop-2017/</guid>
      <description>Summary This is a brief summary and some incomplete reflections from my time as the workshop TA for the 2017 BC Data Science Workshop.
About The BC Data Workshop was hosted August 9 &amp;ndash; 25 in downtown Vancouver at UBC Robson Square, co-organized by myself, Brian Wetton and Lee Rippon from the IAM, with support from PIMS and SFU Mathematics.
The workshop featured a wide array of material from experts across the west coast, structured into three sections: a 3-day pre-workshop intensive; a week of introductory material; and a week-long data science project led by industry mentors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>